to understand all these charts which is
the ability that lets me generate
numbers like these these or even these
simply by anticipating what the next
move will be by reading these
candlesticks and to get to where the
point that I am today it's taken me over
5 years and in this video I will
summarize my whole experience by reading
these charts first of all it is
extremely important to understand what
is a chart so what is a chart it's a
basic tool to see the price movement in
the markets and it is made up of real
price and real time where you can always
chart absolutely any financial asset
this chart allows you to see the live
price of any currency pair any stock any
bond any crypto anything that has a
price move you can see it on a live
chart and now the real question is what
is the real purpose of analyzing these
charts and it is to identify where is
the direction of the market headed so
you're able to guess whether the next
move of the market is going to be to the
upside or to the downside and you're
able to take advantage of that market
opportunity and the goal of all this is
to make money and in order for you to
make money you obviously have to risk
money in trading and to achieve this
there's two simple ways on how to do it
very easy both of these will help you
reach the same end point which is to
understand where is the direction of the
market headed in order for you to go
with it and generate money with it the
first is through fundamental analysis
fundamental analysis serves Us in the
same way to identify the direction of
price but only with a different emphasis
in this case it is done with economic
data or news to cast the direction of
the market and the second which is my
favorite technical analysis technical
analysis is the way to understand the
direction of where the market is headed
but this is by means of these charts
that you see everywhere and this is by
looking at these technical patterns that
happen time and time again in the market
that allows us to understand and
interpret what is going to happen next
in the markets and the absolute first
thing we need to understand in the
market is Trend the trend is your friend
the trend is basically the dominant
movement of the market and the absolute
best way to understand it it is by the
higher highs and the higher lows so the
way you identify a bullish Market is
whether it is creating higher highs and
higher lows heading to the upside
without a higher high or higher low it
is absolutely impossible to have a
bullish Market bullish means that the
market is heading to the upside and then
if you have a bearish market it consists
of lower low lows and then lower highs
it is absolutely impossible to have a
bearish market without lower lows and
lower highs bearish mean sells bullish
mean Buys so now understanding this
which it is extremely key to success in
trading next are the areas of where you
enter a trade there are very specific
zones in price where they have lots of
buying opportunity and selling
opportunity there is very specific zones
in the price where there is lots of
buying or selling interest in the
markets this is where price accumulates
to change the direction of where the
market is headed and there are two types
of areas the first one being support
support is almost as a floor once price
gets to this area it simply can't break
through the floor so what does price do
once it gets to this area it bounces off
so you're always looking to buy price at
a support level in order so you head to
the upside with it the second type is
going to be a resistance resistance is
almost like the roof so once price gets
to the roof it can't break through the
roof so then it rejects it and then it
heads to the downside if you're anytime
looking to buy a market you have to buy
at a support level and if there's any
time that you want to sell you have to
be selling at a resistance which is also
known as the roof and finally we have
the Candlestick patterns Candlestick
patterns are features that are
constantly being repeated in the markets
without ever stopping and this allows us
to interpret what is the market doing in
real time and these patterns make a lot
of of sense at very specific zones for
example you have the pattern of a head
and shoulders a head and shoulders once
it is formed at a resistance level this
is going to indicate that the market is
going to head to the downside so now
that you have a resistance level and on
top of that a reversal pattern it is
very strong indication that you're going
to sell you also have an inverted Head
and Shoulder meaning that you're going
to get an inverted Head and Shoulders at
a support level which is going to
indicate that you're going to bounce off
of that support level stronger than
continua heading to the downside next
you have a break and retest pattern
meaning let's say you have a resistance
level price breaks through the
resistance it retests it it uses it a
support level and then it continues to
head to the upside also for sales let's
say you have a strong support level
price breaks through the support level
comes back and retests it to continue to
head to the downside and there is many
more patterns in the markets that are
used as a reversal pattern to predict
what is the market going to do at a
resistance or at a support level all of
this is more than enough to make your
first analysis in the markets and want
to practice and execute it in real time
so let's put everything into practice
that I've explained to you guys today
the first thing that you want to
understand is whether a market is
bullish or whether a market is bearish
if the market is bullish that means that
it is creating higher highs and higher
lows heading to the upside and if the
market is bearish that means that it is
creating lower lows and lower highs to
the downside after you understand where
the Market is headed up or down then you
need to understand an area of Interest
where you're going to use a strong
support level to then buy or a strong
resistance level to then sell once
you're at this resistance or support
level this is where you're going to
apply the candlesticks to understand a
reversal pattern such as a inverted Head
and Shoulders break and retest double
bottom and much much more and that has
been all for this video today if you
want to know more in depth about my set
and forget strategy that allows me to
generat numbers like these or like these
every single week and it allows
absolutely anybody to generate anywhere
from $1,000 to $11,500 a week using my
set and forget strategy in under 3
months or less click the link in the
description I have a video for you guys
there that is going to explain
everything in great detail so not only
take my word for it but hundreds of my
students that are doing it as well and
living off of trading due to my set and
foret strategy so hope you guys found
this video valuable and I will see you
guys in the next video stay tuned